A Guide to the Peninsula Counselors Association Records, 1996-2010
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Peninsula Counselors Association Records, 1996-2010
The Library of Virginia
50207
1.45 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
Peninsula Counselors Association
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Peninsula Counselors Association, 21 October 2011.
Biographical Information
The Peninsula Counselors Association is a chapter of the Virginia Counselors Association. As stated in its bylaws, the purposes of the organization are (1) to advance the professional and scientific discipline of guidance and counseling, (2) to maintain, improve, and encourage high professional standards and conduct in the field of guidance and counseling, (3) to unite persons engaged or interested in any phase of guidance and counseling activities, functioning through public or private agencies, (4) to function as a central clearing agency for guidance and counseling programs, (5) to disseminate information and focus public attention on legislation which would in any way affect guidance and counseling activities, and the holding of professional meetings, workshops, and conferences. The PCA serves Essex, Gloucester, James City, King and Queen, Mathews, Middlesex, and York Counties, and Hampton, Newport News, Poquoson, and Williamsburg.
Scope and Content
Records, 1996-2010, of the Peninsula Counselors Association, include several scrapbooks, 1996-2009, submitted by the organization as nomination packets for the Virginia Counselors Association Chapter of the Year Award, and a binder (deconstructed) of general records of the organization, 1996-2007, including board minutes, treasurer's reports, program information, and newsletters.
Contents List
- Peninsula Counselors Association Records, 1996-2010., Extent: 1.45 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1996-2009. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - PCA binder (deconstructed), 1996-2007. (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
  - PCA binder (deconstructed), Executive Board, 2003-2004. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nomination package for 2002 VCA Chapter of the Year Award (deconstructed binder), 2001-2002. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's reports and budgets, 1997-1998, 2000-2002, 2005-2008. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Not a comprehensive representation. See also the PCA binders for limited additional reports of this type.
  - VCA Small Chapter of the Year Award (plaque), 2010. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1998-1999. (Box 2)
    PCA's nomination package for 1999 VCA Chapter of the Year Award.
  - Scrapbook, 2006-2007. (Box 2)
    PCA's nomination package for 2007 VCA Chapter of the Year Award.
  - Scrapbook, 2007-2008. (Box 3)
    PCA's nomination package for 2008 VCA Chapter of the Year Award.
  - Scrapbook, 2008-2009. (Box 3)
    PCA's nomination package for 2009 VCA Chapter of the Year Award.